Guide to the Allen G. Kukovich Papers, 1977-2004 AIS.2004.21
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Consumer Protection, 1977-2000; IV.
  - Public Utility Commission Hearing Testimony and Motion to Strike, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Public Utility Consumer Protection Correspondence, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Telephone Deregulation Testimony and Analysis, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Telephone Deregulation Correspondence and Clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Electric Utilities Reform Letter, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Tort Reform Senate Hearing, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Tort Reform Report, 1995-1999 (Box 10, Folder 2-4)
  - Tort Reform Correspondence, 1997-2000 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Pennsylvania Citizens Consumer Council Legislative Priorities, no date (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Criminal and Crime Reform, 1983-2004; V.
  Series V contains materials related to criminal and crime reform. The majority of materials of this series pertain to death penalty reform. Important legislation included under this topic are Post-Conviction DNA Testing, Senate Bill 26 (prohibition of the death penalty for mentally retarded individuals), and a Death Penalty Moratorium. Also included in this series are other criminal reform measures such as earned time and proposed modifications to hate crime and civil rights laws. Specifically, the hate crimes bill expanded the definition of hate crimes to include gender orientation. The majority of materials in this series dates from 1997-2003.
  - Post-Conviction DNA Testing- Bill, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Post-Conviction DNA Testing- Senate Hearing Testimonies, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - Post-Conviction DNA Testing- Memos, 2000-2002 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Post-Conviction DNA Testing- Reports, 2000-2004 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Post-Conviction DNA Testing- Clippings, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Senate Bill 26, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Senate Bill 26- Senate Hearing Testimony, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
  - Senate Bill 26- Correspondence and Fact Sheets, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Senate Bill 26- House Strategy, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Senate Bill 26- District Attorney Memos and Amendments, 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Senate Bill 26- Helfrick and Kukovich Memos, 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Senate Bill 26- ACLU Memos, 2002-2004 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Senate Bill 26- Department of Corrections Letter, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Senate Bill 26- Clippings, 2002-2004 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Senate Bill 26- Pennsylvania Abolitionists United Against the Death Penalty Report, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Senate Bill 26- Support Letters, 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Senate Bill 26- Opposition Letters, 2002-2004 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Senate Bill 26- Bill in Senate, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Senate Bill 26- Fact Sheets and Pamphlets, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Senate Bill 26- Notes, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Senate Bill 26- Letter about a Mentally Retarded Death Row Inmate, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Death Penalty Moratorium Bill and Overview, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Death Penalty Moratorium Senate Hearing, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Senate Hearing Supporting Papers, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Death Penalty Moratorium Strategy and Testimonies, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Hearing Testimony on Racism in Sentencing, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Response Report on Racism in Sentencing, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Pro-Death Penalty Testimony, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Voices of Innocence Rally Tour Materials, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Voices of Innocence Tour Press Coverage, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence Relating Personal Experiences with Death Penalty, 1997-2000 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Innocence Appeals Correspondence, 2000-2002 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence from Religious Institutions, 1989-2001 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Non-Religious Correspondence in Support of Moratorium, 1997-2001 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Reports on the Financial Aspects of the Death Penalty, 1994-2000 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - American Bar Association Death Penalty Stance, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Death Penalty General Facts, 1999-2001 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Opinion Research Poll on Death Penalty, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Death Penalty for Juveniles Bills, 1987-2003 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Female Death Row Inmates Report, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Videotaped Confessions Report, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Death Row Prisoner Misconduct Reports and Clippings, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Police/Prosecutorial Misconduct, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Death Penalty Clippings General, 1995-2003 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Death Penalty Articles, 1987-2001 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Death Penalty Notes, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Earned Time Bills, 1987, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - House Hearing on Earned Time, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Earned Time Reports, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - General Earned Time Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Pennsylvania Prison Society Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Earned Time Clippings, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Witness Competency Bill and Supporting Documents, 1989-1993 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Operation Outward Reach Pamphlets and Reports, 1995-2000 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Operation Outward Reach Press Releases, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Operation Outward Reach Correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - House Resolution to Investigate Hate Crimes, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Hate Crimes Research, 1994-1997 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Letter to House Democrats about Hearing, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Militia Testimonies, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Kukovich Tolerance Meeting with Faith Leaders, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Faith Leaders' Hate Crime Correspondence and Memos, 1998-2000 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Faith Leaders Articles, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Anti-Mask Legislation, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Civil Rights Expansion Bill, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Civil Rights Expansion Bill Research, 1997-2000 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Civil Rights Expansion Media, 1997-2002 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence with Pennsylvania Lesbian and Gay Task Force, 1998-2001 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Civil Rights Expansion Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Civil Rights Expansion Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Litigation to Overturn the Civil Rights Expansion Act, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 39-40)
  - Religious Freedom Protection Act Correspondence and Clippings, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Pennsylvania Commission on Crime and Delinquency Bill, 1983-1993 (Box 11, Folder 42)
- Children's Issues, 1985-2003; VI.
  Series VI consists of materials related to Children's Issues. Kukovich served as co-chair of the Children's Caucus beginning in 1985, and his papers contain a significant amount of reports, hearings, and research on various children's issues that are reflected in this series. Of greatest depth are organizational papers and reports from the Children's Trust Fund and legislation concerning education programs. For CHIP (Children's Health Insurance Program) papers, see Series II: Health Care).
  - Pennsylvania Children's Caucus, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 1-6)
  - Summary of Pennsylvania Programs for Women and Children, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Children's Budget Highlights, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Act and Fact Sheets, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Board ByLaws and Work Plan, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Board Meeting Minutes, 1990-2003 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Grant Requests, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Annual Reports, 1994-1999 (Box 12, Folder 13-18)
  - Children's Trust Fund- State Plan, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Annual Report, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Children's Trust Fund- State Plan, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Annual Report, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Children's Trust Fund- State Plan, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Performance Audit, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Hearing and Testimony, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Correspondence, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Children's Trust Fund- Press Releases and Clippings, 1985-1989 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Child Abuse Bill, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Child Protective Services Hearings, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 29-31)
  - Child Protective Services Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Child Protective Services Expansion Bill, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Child Support Legislation, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Adoption Legislation, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Women Infants, and Children Fund- Bills, 1986-2001 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Women Infants, and Children Fund- Correspondence, Memos, and Notes, 1986-1999 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Women Infants, and Children Fund- Clippings and Press Releases, 1986-2001 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Women Infants, and Children Fund- Pamphlets, 1990-1995 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Head Start- Bills, 1991-1999 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Head Start- House Hearing Testimony, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Head Start- Correspondence and Reports, 1985-2003 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Head Start- Press Releases and Clippings, 1989-2000 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Child Care- Bills, 1998-2001 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Child Care- Press Releases, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Child Care- Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Child Care- Workshop, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Early Education Concerns, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Education Advisory Board Papers, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - General Assembly Special Session on Education, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Fair Chance Schools Plan and Research, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Early Childhood Education Hearing, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Secondary Education Costs Legislation, 1993-1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Education Constituent Correspondence, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - School-to-Work Strategy, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Summit in Westmoreland, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
  - Committee the School-to-Work Partnership Papers, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - School-to-Work Brochures and Reports, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - School-to-Work Career Fair Plans, 1996-1998 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Workforce Development Hearings and Seminars, 1997, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - House Hearing on Parental Consent for Abortions for Minors, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Teen Abortion Research, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - State Initiatives for Parenting Teens, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Committee to Investigate Teen Suicide Report, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania Suicide Prevention Plan, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Newborn Health Screening Program Act, 1989-1992 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Delinquent Bill, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 25)
- Political Reform, 1979-2003; VII.
  Series VII contains materials related to political reform. Reform of the political process was one of Kukovich's career-long crusades. Of primary interest was campaign finance reform, which is the strongest topic in this series. Papers relating to two organizations need mentioning here, namely Common Cause (a nonpartisan nonprofit advocacy organization) and The Democracy Project (started by Kukovich to increase the accountability of government leaders and promote access to the political process). Most of the papers in this collection were created in the 1990s.
  - Campaign Finance Reform- Bills, 1991-1997 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Campaign Finance Reform- Kukovich's Role, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Campaign Finance Reform- Talking Points, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Campaign Finance Reform- House Hearing, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Campaign Finance Reform- Research, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Campaign Finance Reform- PowerPoint Presentation, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Campaign Finance Reform- Speech to League of Women Voters, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Campaign Finance Reform- State Supreme Court Report, 1998-2001 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Campaign Finance Reform- Press Releases, 1987-1996 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Campaign Finance Reform- Clippings, 1993-1996 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Campaign Finance Reform- Papers, 1979, 1993-2003 (Box 13, Folder 36-45)
  - Book - Money and Politics: Financing Our Elections Democratically, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Common Cause, 1980-1990 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Lobbyist Disclosure Legislation, 1983-1990 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Electorate Forum Discussion, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - The Democracy Project Papers, 1996-2001 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Homeless Voter Registration Bills, 1988-1992 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Homeless Voter Registration Correspondence and Clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Independents Vote in Primary Bill, 1997-1999 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Reapportionment Bill and Plan, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Reapportionment Clippings, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Bill to Change Date of Primaries, 1981-1999 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Commonwealth Right to Jury Trial Bill, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Senate Hearing-Right of the Commonwealth to Jury Trial, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Commonwealth Right to Jury Trial Research, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Commonwealth Right to Jury Trial Talking Points, 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Budgetary Process Legislation, 1990-1996 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Independent Regulatory Review Commission, 1981-2002 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - General Assembly Reduction Legislation, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - General Election Issues, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Municipal Grant Profiles, 1989-2004; X.
    Scope and Contents note
    Series X. contains municipal grant profiles and is the only series in the collection that remains organized as it was originally organized by Kukovich's office staff. Each file folder contains information on a grant that Kukovich assisted in securing for a municipality (or regional organization). The grant profiles are arranged in alphabetical order by the towns to which they applied. A good overview of Kukovich's work in grant funding work is available in the first file folder of the series, which is a booklet containing a list of all of the grants he successfully assisted with from 1997-2000. The booklet is organized by town and includes the grant names, years obtained, project overview, grant type, and amount of funding.
    - Municipal Grant Profiles, 1997-2000 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Belle Vernon, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Conemaugh, Loyalhanna, Saltsburg, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - East Huntingdon, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Greensburg, 1996-2003 (Box 14, Folder 38-43)
    - Harrisburg, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Hempfield, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Jeanette, 1992-1998 (Box 14, Folder 46-48)
    - Larimer, 1991-1995 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Latrobe, 1998-2004 (Box 16, Folder 2-6)
    - Loyalhanna, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Manor, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Mon Valley, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Mount Pleasant, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
    - New Alexandria, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - New Stanton, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - North Huntingdon, 1990-1999 (Box 16, Folder 14-16)
    - Penn Borough, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Penn Township, 1999-2001 (Box 16, Folder 18-19)
    - Rostraver, 1998-2000 (Box 16, Folder 20-21)
    - Smithton, 1997-2001 (Box 16, Folder 22-23)
    - South Huntingdon, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Unity, 1998-2001 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Westmoreland, 1989-2004 (Box 16, Folder 26-44)
    - West Newton, 1996-2001 (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
    - York, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Youghiogheny Trail, 1997-1999 (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
    - Youngstown, 1997-1999 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - Youngwood, 1998-2002 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Misc. DCED Grants, 1998-2001 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Misc. PIC Grants, 1997-1998 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Misc. Grants, 1997-1998 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Economic Development, 1983-2000; VIII.
  Series VIII consists of materials related to economic development. This small series contains correspondence, bills, clippings, and reports on various strategies for regional and municipal economic development. As the steel industry filtered out of western Pennsylvania in the 1980s, the state legislature sought ways to rebuild the region; some of their plans, including Regional Renaissance and Plan B, are outlined in this series. Regional Renaissance was a plan to create jobs and preserve regional assets by investing in infrastructure and regional attractions. Plan B aimed at raising funds for a new stadium and convention center. Kukovich also supported the protection of workers under legislation that would require advanced notification of plant shut-downs.
  - Economic Development Strategy, 1984-1998 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Economic Development Position, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Economic Development Goals and Projects, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Southwestern Pennsylvania Growth Alliance Correspondence, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Southwestern Regional Planning Commission Presentation, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Southwestern Pennsylvania Commission Correspondence, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Regional Development Financial Subcommittee Paper, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Regional Planning Research and Notes, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Economic Conversion- Bills, 1987-1993 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Economic Conversion- National Commission Speech, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Economic Conversion- Memos, 1987-1997 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Economic Conversion- Correspondence, 1987-1993 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Economic Conversion- Clippings, 1990-1993 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Notification of Plant Closings- Bills, 198-1995 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Notification of Plant Closings- Correspondence and Memos, 1983-1993 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Notification of Plant Closings- Clippings, 1983-1990 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Notification of Plant Closings- Kukovich Testimony, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Regional Renaissance- Legislation, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Regional Renaissance- Correspondence, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Regional Renaissance- Clippings, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Regional Renaissance- TV Editorials, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Plan B Outline, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Plan B News Conference, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Plan B Correspondence and Clippings, 1997-1999 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Roundtable Discussion on the Region's Future, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Borrowing for Capital Facilities Bill, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Plan B Funding, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Local Development Districts Report, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Industrial Development Report, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Regional Economic Revitalization Index, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Downtown Development Bill, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - University of Pittsburgh Fiscal Needs, 1999-2000 (Box 17, Folder 51)
- Poverty, 1985-2003; IX.
  Series IX contains materials related to poverty. Legislation concerning affordable housing, raising the minimum wage, and hunger are found in the Poverty series. Papers relating to several organizations are also here. Most important to Kukovich's life was the Pennsylvania Institute on Public Policy (PIPP), which he organized in 1989. The goal of the organization, according to their mission statement, was to develop and promote effective and progressive policies to decrease poverty and enable low-income Pennsylvanians to achieve a decent standard of living. The other acronym whose full name is important in understanding this series in LIHEAP, or Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program.
  - Pennsylvania Institute on Public Policy (PIPP), Organizational Information, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - (PIPP), Dislocated Worker Project, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - (PIPP), Rural Poverty Research, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - (PIPP), State Agenda and Revenue Plan, 1993, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - (PIPP), Correspondence, 1987-1995 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - (PIPP), Press Releases, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - (PIPP), Clippings, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Welfare Reports, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - PA Welfare Coalition Papers, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Public Interest Institute Papers, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Homeowner's Emergency Mortgage Assistance Fund Legislation, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Affordable Housing- Trust Fund Bill, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Affordable Housing- Research and Planning, 1991-1993 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Affordable Housing- Five Year Study, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Affordable Housing- State Reports, 1990, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Affordable Housing- Clippings, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Affordable Housing- Notes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Manufactured Housing House Hearing, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - LIHEAP Bills, 1985-1993 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - LIHEAP Committee Reports, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - LIHEAP Correspondence, 1987-1994 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - HIHEAP Press Releases and Clippings, 1985-1989 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Human Services Development Fund Bill, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Human Services Coalition Organizational Papers, 1990-1996 (Box 15, Folder 24-27)
  - Human Services Coalition Clippings, 1990-1993 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Legal Task Force for the Needy Papers, 1990-1993 (Box 15, Folder 29-31)
  - Hunger Issues, 1986, 2002-2003 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Minimum Wage Legislation, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 33)
- Other Initiatives and Organizational Involvements, 1981-2004; XI.
  Series XI contains important legislation and Kukovich's various organizational memberships that did not easily fall into the specific categories above. A single file folder containing mostly correspondence sheds light on the views of the Congressman and his constituents on the controversial issue of the legalization of gambling in the city. The one legislative issue with significant documentation is the SERVIS (Seniors Earning Rebates Volunteering in Schools) program developed by Allen. In lieu of accepting a pay raise in the late 1980s, Kukovich established a public service scholarship program for high school seniors. Application information, correspondence, press releases, clippings, and photos about the scholarship from mixed years (1989-2004) are found here.
  Kukovich also belonged to many organizations over his years in the legislature, papers documenting this involvement are included in this series. Among them are those collected during his time on the Board of Directors of WQED, Pittsburgh's PBS station; the Public Interest Law Group for which he served as Vice President in 1986; and the Pennsylvania Alliance for Democracy (PAD). Though the details of membership and mission are unclear from the contents of this collection, Kukovich also started what he termed "The Breakfast Club" to discuss budgetary issues from 1998-2002.
  - Kukovich Scholarship- Application Information, 1995-2003 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Kukovich Scholarship- Correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Kukovich Scholarship- Clippings and Press Releases, 1996-2002 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Kukovich Scholarship- Fundraisers, 1998-2002 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Kukovich Scholarship-Photos, 1989-2004 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - WQED- Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - WQED- Reports, 1995-1997 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - WQED- Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - WQED- Press Releases, 1995, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - PAD Meeting Minutes, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - PAD Correspondence, 2000-2002 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - PAD Publications, 2000-2003 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Breakfast Club Correspondence, 1998-2002 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Pittsburgh Public Interest Law Group Organizational Papers, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 27)